<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Phonetics | MIRer</title>
    <link>/tags/phonetics/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tags/phonetics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Phonetics</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:19:18 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hu25a3ac0bff28d67894e084ca1bc4b864_11852_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Phonetics</title>
      <link>/tags/phonetics/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>TONE CONTOUR REALIZATION IN SUNG CANTONESE</title>
      <link>/project/phonetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:19:18 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/phonetics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nov. 2019 &amp;ndash; Jan. 2020. Beijing, CHN.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Class project&lt;/em&gt;, scored 92/100. Supervised by Associate prof. &lt;a href=&#39;https://chinese.pku.edu.cn/rwfc/1224333.htm&#39; target=&#39;_blank&#39;&gt;WANG Yunjia&lt;/a&gt;, department of Chinese Language and Literature, Peking University.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Final project of &lt;em&gt;Fundamental Chinese Phonetics&lt;/em&gt; course: A brief discussion on the relationship between the basic frequency and the lyric tone of Cantonese songs (class final paper see at &lt;a href=&#39;../../files/略论粤语歌曲基频与歌词声调的关联.pdf&#39; target=&#39;_blank&#39;&gt;略论粤语歌曲基频与歌词声调的关联&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on &lt;a href=&#39;https://pan.baidu.com/s/1hjZrIAGYvPX7zviB87aeFA&#39; target=&#39;_blank&#39;&gt;acoustic phonetics data&lt;/a&gt;(extraction code &amp;ldquo;uwr8&amp;rdquo; if needed), this paper discusses the influence of the fundamental frequency of cantonese songs on the tone of the lyrics. Eleven phonators (6 female and 5 male) aged between 18 and 22 years old were analyzed for the singing and lyric reading sound of the designated song, to explore the change of fundamental frequency over time, and the study tone involved four of the six tones in Cantonese.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;paires t-test&lt;/em&gt; of the acoustic data showed that :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there was a significant difference in the slope of the fundamental frequency of lyric reading over time in tones with different tone values;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is no significant difference in the slope of the fundamental frequency of the song over time between the lyrics of each tone;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a certain relationship between the basic frequency slope of each tone and the basic frequency slope of the song.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Correspondence between Speech Melody and Pitch Contour in Sichuan Folk Song</title>
      <link>/project/duan_zhiyao/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 00:19:03 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/duan_zhiyao/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jul. 2019 – Sept. 2019. Rochester, NY, US.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Research Assistant supervised by &lt;a href=&#39;http://www2.ece.rochester.edu/~zduan/&#39; target=&#39;_blank&#39;&gt;prof. DUAN Zhiyao&lt;/a&gt;, Deparment of Electronic Computer Engineer, University of Rochester.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Main Information&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Made a literature review of linguistics papers on relations between speech melody and notes in tone language song.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set up a database on Sichuan folk song with music scores in MusicXML form, lyrics audio in Sichuan dialect in wav form and note-audio alignment character by character.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analyzed the correspondence among the tone of each character, the change of fundamental frequency of each character audio and the change of music notes linked to it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evaluated different correspondence rates in different type of folk songs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
