<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Other | MIRer</title>
    <link>/tags/other/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tags/other/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Other</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 22:05:06 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hu25a3ac0bff28d67894e084ca1bc4b864_11852_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Other</title>
      <link>/tags/other/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Time-Variant Reverberation Algorithm for Reverberation Enhancement Syetem</title>
      <link>/project/reverb/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 22:05:06 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/reverb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The reverberation algorithm is usually an LTI system. The room in the concert hall does not
change, so the response does not change over time. However, this can lead to colouration and
instability due to feedback caused by the close proximity of the microphones and speakers. Some
time-varying systems can solve this problem. This paper implements a new time-varying variable
reverberation algorithm on bela, based on a combination of delay-line, lowpass filter and comb
filter and feedback, for reverberation enhancement systems. Such systems can often be used in
electroacoustically enhanced rehearsal rooms. This particular application is briefly outlined, and
other possible applications are discussed while the shortcomings of the experimental approach are
analysed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#39;../../files/map.mp4&#39; target=&#39;_blank&#39;&gt;Demo recoding&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cover Song Detection &amp; Evaluation of Automatic Speech Recognition</title>
      <link>/project/teencent2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 21:49:27 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/teencent2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;May 2020 &amp;ndash; Aug. 2021. Beijing, CHN. Summer internship in Tencent Holdings Limited. (Beijing)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write literature review on coversong detection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reproduced and refined music separation &amp;amp; covering detection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Evaluating different ASR models on business data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TONE CONTOUR REALIZATION IN SUNG CANTONESE</title>
      <link>/project/phonetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:19:18 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/phonetics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nov. 2019 &amp;ndash; Jan. 2020. Beijing, CHN.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Class project&lt;/em&gt;, scored 92/100. Supervised by Associate prof. &lt;a href=&#39;https://chinese.pku.edu.cn/rwfc/1224333.htm&#39; target=&#39;_blank&#39;&gt;WANG Yunjia&lt;/a&gt;, department of Chinese Language and Literature, Peking University.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Final project of &lt;em&gt;Fundamental Chinese Phonetics&lt;/em&gt; course: A brief discussion on the relationship between the basic frequency and the lyric tone of Cantonese songs (class final paper see at &lt;a href=&#39;../../files/略论粤语歌曲基频与歌词声调的关联.pdf&#39; target=&#39;_blank&#39;&gt;略论粤语歌曲基频与歌词声调的关联&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on &lt;a href=&#39;https://pan.baidu.com/s/1hjZrIAGYvPX7zviB87aeFA&#39; target=&#39;_blank&#39;&gt;acoustic phonetics data&lt;/a&gt;(extraction code &amp;ldquo;uwr8&amp;rdquo; if needed), this paper discusses the influence of the fundamental frequency of cantonese songs on the tone of the lyrics. Eleven phonators (6 female and 5 male) aged between 18 and 22 years old were analyzed for the singing and lyric reading sound of the designated song, to explore the change of fundamental frequency over time, and the study tone involved four of the six tones in Cantonese.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;paires t-test&lt;/em&gt; of the acoustic data showed that :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there was a significant difference in the slope of the fundamental frequency of lyric reading over time in tones with different tone values;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is no significant difference in the slope of the fundamental frequency of the song over time between the lyrics of each tone;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a certain relationship between the basic frequency slope of each tone and the basic frequency slope of the song.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
