<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GenAI | MIRer</title>
    <link>/tags/genai/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tags/genai/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>GenAI</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 18:24:35 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hu25a3ac0bff28d67894e084ca1bc4b864_11852_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>GenAI</title>
      <link>/tags/genai/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>ComposerX: Multi-Agent Symbolic Music Composition with LLMs</title>
      <link>/publication/composorx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 18:24:35 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/composorx/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract: Music composition represents the creative side of humanity, and itself is a complex task that requires abilities to understand and generate information with long dependency and harmony constraints. Current LLMs often struggle with this task, sometimes generating poorly written music even when equipped with modern techniques like InContext-Learning and Chain-of-Thoughts. To further explore and enhance LLMs’ potential in music composition by leveraging their reasoning ability and the large knowledge base in music history and theory, we propose ComposerX 1 , an agent-based symbolic music generation framework. We find that applying a multi-agent approach significantly improves the music composition quality of GPT-4. The results demonstrate that ComposerX is capable of producing coherent polyphonic music compositions with captivating melodies, while adhering to user instructions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://qmro.qmul.ac.uk/xmlui/bitstream/handle/123456789/98627/Benetos%20ComposerX%3A%20Multi-Agent%20Symbolic%20Music%20Composition%20with%20LLMs%202024%20Published.pdf?sequence=2&amp;isAllowed=y&#34; arget=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Paper link.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PUblished in the 25th International Society for Music Information Retrieval (ISMIR 2024).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
