<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Multimodal | MIRer</title>
    <link>/tags/multimodal/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tags/multimodal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Multimodal</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2025 18:24:35 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hu25a3ac0bff28d67894e084ca1bc4b864_11852_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Multimodal</title>
      <link>/tags/multimodal/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>CMI-Bench: A Comprehensive Benchmark for Evaluating Music Instruction Following</title>
      <link>/publication/cmi-bench/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2025 18:24:35 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/cmi-bench/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract: Recent advances in audio-text large language models (LLMs) have opened new possibilities for music understanding and generation. However, existing benchmarks are limited in scope, often relying on simplified tasks or multi-choice evaluations that fail to reflect the complexity of real-world music analysis. We reinterpret a broad range of traditional MIR annotations as instruction-following formats and introduce CMI-Bench, a comprehensive music instruction following benchmark designed to evaluate audio-text LLMs on a diverse set of music information retrieval (MIR) tasks. These include genre classification, emotion regression, emotion tagging, instrument classification, pitch estimation, key detection, lyrics transcription, melody extraction, vocal technique recognition, instrument performance technique detection, music tagging, music captioning, and (down)beat tracking: reflecting core challenges in MIR research. Unlike previous benchmarks, CMI-Bench adopts standardized evaluation metrics consistent with previous state-of-the-art MIR models, ensuring direct comparability with supervised approaches. We provide an evaluation toolkit supporting all open-source audio-textual LLMs, including LTU, Qwen-audio, SALMONN, MusiLingo, etc. Experiment results reveal significant performance gaps between LLMs and supervised models, along with their culture, chronological and gender bias, highlighting the potential and limitations of current models in addressing MIR tasks. CMI-Bench establishes a unified foundation for evaluating music instruction following, driving progress in music-aware LLMs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arxiv.org/abs/2506.12285&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Paper link.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nicolaus625/CMI-bench&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Code link.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://huggingface.co/datasets/nicolaus625/CMI-bench&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Dataset link.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PUblished in the 26th International Society for Music Information Retrieval (ISMIR 2025).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MMAR: A Challenging Benchmark for Deep Reasoning in Speech, Audio, Music, and Their Mix</title>
      <link>/publication/mmar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 18:24:35 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/mmar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract: We introduce MMAR, a new benchmark designed to evaluate the deep reasoning capabilities of Audio-Language Models (ALMs) across massive multi-disciplinary tasks. MMAR comprises 1,000 meticulously curated audio-question-answer triplets, collected from real-world internet videos and refined through iterative error corrections and quality checks to ensure high quality. Unlike existing benchmarks that are limited to specific domains of sound, music, or speech, MMAR extends them to a broad spectrum of real-world audio scenarios, including mixed-modality combinations of sound, music, and speech. Each question in MMAR is hierarchically categorized across four reasoning layers: Signal, Perception, Semantic, and Cultural, with additional sub-categories within each layer to reflect task diversity and complexity. To further foster research in this area, we annotate every question with a Chain-of-Thought (CoT) rationale to promote future advancements in audio reasoning. Each item in the benchmark demands multi-step deep reasoning beyond surface-level understanding. Moreover, a part of the questions requires graduate-level perceptual and domain-specific knowledge, elevating the benchmark&#39;s difficulty and depth. We evaluate MMAR using a broad set of models, including Large Audio-Language Models (LALMs), Large Audio Reasoning Models (LARMs), Omni Language Models (OLMs), Large Language Models (LLMs), and Large Reasoning Models (LRMs), with audio caption inputs. The performance of these models on MMAR highlights the benchmark&#39;s challenging nature, and our analysis further reveals critical limitations of …&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/pdf/2505.13032&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Paper link.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ddlBoJack/MMAR&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Code link.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yue: Scaling open foundation models for long-form music generation</title>
      <link>/publication/yue/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 18:24:35 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/yue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract: We tackle the task of long-form music generation&amp;ndash;particularly the challenging \textbf{lyrics-to-song} problem&amp;ndash;by introducing YuE, a family of open foundation models based on the LLaMA2 architecture. Specifically, YuE scales to trillions of tokens and generates up to five minutes of music while maintaining lyrical alignment, coherent musical structure, and engaging vocal melodies with appropriate accompaniment. It achieves this through (1) track-decoupled next-token prediction to overcome dense mixture signals, (2) structural progressive conditioning for long-context lyrical alignment, and (3) a multitask, multiphase pre-training recipe to converge and generalize. In addition, we redesign the in-context learning technique for music generation, enabling versatile style transfer (e.g., converting Japanese city pop into an English rap while preserving the original accompaniment) and bidirectional generation. Through extensive evaluation, we demonstrate that YuE matches or even surpasses some of the proprietary systems in musicality and vocal agility. In addition, fine-tuning YuE enables additional controls and enhanced support for tail languages. Furthermore, beyond generation, we show that YuE&#39;s learned representations can perform well on music understanding tasks, where the results of YuE match or exceed state-of-the-art methods on the MARBLE benchmark. Keywords: lyrics2song, song generation, long-form, foundation model, music generation&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Audio-flan: A preliminary release</title>
      <link>/publication/audio-flan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 18:24:35 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/audio-flan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract: 
Recent advancements in audio tokenization have significantly enhanced the integration of audio capabilities into large language models (LLMs). However, audio understanding and generation are often treated as distinct tasks, hindering the development of truly unified audio-language models. While instruction tuning has demonstrated remarkable success in improving generalization and zero-shot learning across text and vision, its application to audio remains largely unexplored. A major obstacle is the lack of comprehensive datasets that unify audio understanding and generation. To address this, we introduce Audio-FLAN, a large-scale instruction-tuning dataset covering 80 diverse tasks across speech, music, and sound domains, with over 100 million instances. Audio-FLAN lays the foundation for unified audio-language models that can seamlessly handle both understanding (e.g., transcription, comprehension) and generation (e.g., speech, music, sound) tasks across a wide range of audio domains in a zero-shot manner. The Audio-FLAN dataset is available on HuggingFace and GitHub and will be continuously updated.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Omnibench: Towards the future of universal omni-language models</title>
      <link>/publication/omnibench/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 18:24:35 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/omnibench/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract: 
Recent advancements in multimodal large language models (MLLMs) have focused on integrating multiple modalities, yet their ability to simultaneously process and reason across different inputs remains underexplored. We introduce OmniBench, a novel benchmark designed to evaluate models&amp;rsquo; ability to recognize, interpret, and reason across visual, acoustic, and textual inputs simultaneously. We define language models capable of such tri-modal processing as omni-language models (OLMs). OmniBench features high-quality human annotations that require integrated understanding across all modalities. Our evaluation reveals that: i) open-source OLMs show significant limitations in instruction-following and reasoning in tri-modal contexts; and ii) most baseline models perform poorly (around 50% accuracy) even with textual alternatives to image/audio inputs. To address these limitations, we develop OmniInstruct, an 96K-sample instruction tuning dataset for training OLMs. We advocate for developing more robust tri-modal integration techniques and training strategies to enhance OLM performance. Codes and data could be found at our repo (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/multimodal-art-projection/OmniBench)&#34;&gt;https://github.com/multimodal-art-projection/OmniBench)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.15272&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Paper link.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/multimodal-art-projection/OmniBench&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Code link.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foundation models for music: A survey</title>
      <link>/publication/fm4music/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 18:24:35 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/fm4music/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract: In recent years, foundation models (FMs) such as large language models (LLMs) and latent diffusion models (LDMs) have profoundly impacted diverse sectors, including music. This comprehensive review examines state-of-the-art (SOTA) pre-trained models and foundation models in music, spanning from representation learning, generative learning and multimodal learning. We first contextualise the significance of music in various industries and trace the evolution of AI in music. By delineating the modalities targeted by foundation models, we discover many of the music representations are underexplored in FM development. Then, emphasis is placed on the lack of versatility of previous methods on diverse music applications, along with the potential of FMs in music understanding, generation and medical application. By comprehensively exploring the details of the model pre-training paradigm, architectural choices, tokenisation, finetuning methodologies and controllability, we emphasise the important topics that should have been well explored, like instruction tuning and in-context learning, scaling law and emergent ability, as well as long-sequence modelling etc. A dedicated section presents insights into music agents, accompanied by a thorough analysis of datasets and evaluations essential for pre-training and downstream tasks. Finally, by underscoring the vital importance of ethical considerations, we advocate that following research on FM for music should focus more on such issues as interpretability, transparency, human responsibility, and copyright issues. The paper offers insights into future challenges and trends on FMs for music …&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nicolaus625/FM4Music&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Code link.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Huggingface daily paper top 3, 27 Aug 2024.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can LLMs &#34;Reason&#34; in Music? An Evaluation of LLMs&#39; Capability of Music Understanding and Generation</title>
      <link>/publication/reason/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 18:24:35 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/reason/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract: Symbolic Music, akin to language, can be encoded in discrete symbols. Recent research has extended the application of large language models (LLMs) such as GPT-4 and Llama2 to the symbolic music domain including understanding and generation. Yet scant research explores the details of how these LLMs perform on advanced music understanding and conditioned generation, especially from the multi-step reasoning perspective, which is a critical aspect in the conditioned, editable, and interactive human-computer co-creation process. This study conducts a thorough investigation of LLMs’ capability and limitations in symbolic music processing. We identify that current LLMs exhibit poor performance in song-level multi-step music reasoning, and typically fail to leverage learned music knowledge when addressing complex musical tasks. An analysis of LLMs’ responses highlights distinctly their pros and cons. Our findings suggest achieving advanced musical capability is not intrinsically obtained by LLMs, and future research should focus more on bridging the gap between music knowledge and reasoning, to improve the co-creation experience for musicians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/html/2407.21531v1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Paper link.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PUblished in the 25th International Society for Music Information Retrieval (ISMIR 2024).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ComposerX: Multi-Agent Symbolic Music Composition with LLMs</title>
      <link>/publication/composorx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 18:24:35 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/composorx/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract: Music composition represents the creative side of humanity, and itself is a complex task that requires abilities to understand and generate information with long dependency and harmony constraints. Current LLMs often struggle with this task, sometimes generating poorly written music even when equipped with modern techniques like InContext-Learning and Chain-of-Thoughts. To further explore and enhance LLMs’ potential in music composition by leveraging their reasoning ability and the large knowledge base in music history and theory, we propose ComposerX 1 , an agent-based symbolic music generation framework. We find that applying a multi-agent approach significantly improves the music composition quality of GPT-4. The results demonstrate that ComposerX is capable of producing coherent polyphonic music compositions with captivating melodies, while adhering to user instructions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://qmro.qmul.ac.uk/xmlui/bitstream/handle/123456789/98627/Benetos%20ComposerX%3A%20Multi-Agent%20Symbolic%20Music%20Composition%20with%20LLMs%202024%20Published.pdf?sequence=2&amp;isAllowed=y&#34; arget=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Paper link.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PUblished in the 25th International Society for Music Information Retrieval (ISMIR 2024).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chatmusician: Understanding and generating music intrinsically with LLM</title>
      <link>/publication/chatmusician/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2024 18:24:35 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/chatmusician/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract: While Large Language Models (LLMs) demonstrate impressive capabilities in text generation, we find that their ability has yet to be generalized to music, humanity&#39;s creative language. We introduce ChatMusician, an open-source LLM that integrates intrinsic musical abilities. It is based on continual pre-training and finetuning LLaMA2 on a text-compatible music representation, ABC notation, and the music is treated as a second language. ChatMusician can understand and generate music with a pure text tokenizer without any external multi-modal neural structures or tokenizers. Interestingly, endowing musical abilities does not harm language abilities, even achieving a slightly higher MMLU score. Our model is capable of composing well-structured, full-length music, conditioned on texts, chords, melodies, motifs, musical forms, etc, surpassing GPT-4 baseline. On our meticulously curated college-level music understanding benchmark, MusicTheoryBench, ChatMusician surpasses LLaMA2 and GPT-3.5 on zero-shot setting by a noticeable margin. Our work reveals that LLMs can be an excellent compressor for music, but there remains significant territory to be conquered. We release our 4B token music-language corpora MusicPile, the collected MusicTheoryBench, code, model and demo in GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bridging Music &amp; Text with Pre-trained Models for Music Captioning and QA</title>
      <link>/project/musilingo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 21:40:17 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/musilingo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;07/2023 – present&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supervised by Dr Emmanouil Benetos, Centre for Digital Music, Queen Mary University of London&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developed Music Instruct (MI) query-response dataset based on captions &amp;amp; well-designed prompts to GPT-4.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Achieved cutting-edge performance in question answering on both MusicQA and Music Instruct datasets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Employed instruct fine-tuning techniques on MI to attain state-of-the-art (SOTA) results in captioning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MusiLingo: Bridging Music and Text with Pre-trained Language Models for Music Captioning and Query Response</title>
      <link>/publication/musilingo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 18:24:35 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/musilingo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) have shown immense potential in multimodal applications, yet the convergence of textual and musical domains remains relatively unexplored. To address this gap, we present MusiLingo, a novel system for music caption generation and music-related query responses. MusiLingo employs a single projection layer to align music representations from the pre-trained frozen music audio model MERT with the frozen LLaMA language model, bridging the gap between music audio and textual contexts. We train it on an extensive music caption dataset and fine-tune it with instructional data. Due to the scarcity of high-quality music Q&amp;amp;A datasets, we created the MusicInstruct (MI) dataset from MusicCaps, tailored for open-ended music inquiries. Empirical evaluations demonstrate its competitive performance in generating music captions and composing music-related Q&amp;amp;A pairs. Our introduced dataset enables notable advancements beyond previous ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/pdf/2309.08730.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Paper link.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zihaod/musilingo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Code link.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://huggingface.co/datasets/m-a-p/Music-Instruct/tree/main&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Dataset link.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PUblished in 2024 Annual Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (NAACL 2024).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
